Everybody, this is Coder Henry B H, and I have
well, I mostly developed a
version of scratch coding its block coding, but
I just want to show you I just want to help you
understand exactly what typed coding is.
Typed coding is kind of a phrase I made up, but it's
exactly what it is. It's typed code. So one of
these is JavaScript and I'm just going to give you
an example. scratch we would to do an equation.
We have an equation block. It's a green block or
so blank plus blank. And then we would put that in
a say. So one flag clicked say blah blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. In this case, we're going
to use nine plus five
and so on JavaScript we would do that println(data);
we put the data that we want to do the
equation in five plus nine and it would write it
as 14 on the screen, um, not in code on this part
of the code. So
I'm just going to show you what my typed version
of Scratch, which I'm going to call TSCL
typed scratch computer language TSCL.
it's pronounced /tsil/.
That is the um this right here is the IPA and it's
exactly it's TSCL. OK, all right. Let's go
ahead and start typing this. So
this, this starts everything off. When I have that
a
dollar sign I'm going to go and start typing in
here. So we're going to um there these things
where I can go like this.
So anybody reading this who actually knows the
language, they will be like, oh yeah, this block
has to do with, um, sound or if it's like this. Oh
yeah. This book definitely has to do with, uh,
looks and oh no, this has to do with motion et
cetera. Well actually it's mostly just those three
for anything else, like an event block we could do
event because those that there's question
exclamation marks are comments. And if maybe
there's a block that looks the same as another
block, but it's for a different thing and a
different type of block, we could tell the
computer what it is. I mean, you don't usually
need to do that, but we would do this. So we would
say event. It also helps the reader, but it also
helps the computer. I could write whatever I want
in this comment. It's not really code. So I could
write, I could write, "I love scratch"
I could write, um,
I could even write this.
Which is the symbol for which is the hide block,
and it wouldn't do anything because it's comenting
right back. OK, so I'm just going to go ahead and
show you what it's going to be like. So we're
going to go ahead and put that here. We're going
to do I want to tell the reader that this is a
hide block. So hide, I mean,
a looks block. And then we're going to go and put
this here and then we're going to put a semicolon
to tell them that it's the end of a block. Then we
have to know.
Go and do this, and then we're going to do this
again, but let's say I don't I want to make a
comment. No, no, I need to tell the computer so.
OK, and so if you know JavaScript.
You probably knew about the separating words with
capital letters thing,
which I'm going to use in the scratch. OK, so and
what we have to put this thing in here now in
order to tell the computer that it's
that it's kind of a drop down thing. It's got some
choices. We have to put this signs, anything like
this for this we're going to put in for this. Here,
let me speak. Hello? Are you going to put an
ampersand? Now, this is the same, but we're going
to put a hash tag or number sign because this is a
number if we were. But we're not to that point yet.
So we're going to put this hash. I mean, present
here. We want to put thank you. And then, uh, and
a block and now we're going to write this and all
that good computer. I think the computer knows
this. So reach and then we have to put the numbers
in here, but we don't have to we could just put
the regular ampersand, but it it helps the
computer know that it's specifically in number and
it could sometimes work wrong. So zero point five.
Seconds.
Um.
And, Brooke, um, and really we can just use curly
brackets like this.
Or if you're in a typewriter, uh, I could just do
this because typewriters don't actually help this,
the brackets or curly brackets. So we're going to
put, um, but we're going to do creeley records
because this is a computer, um, probably work
better. I make computer less confused. All right.
So that should wait. And then we're going to go
and show. No show.
And switch costume to
and then because it's kind of a drop down thing,
we got to do that present sign
and then name, costume one and block.
And switch. Back
drop to.
Left talking
now, because this is kind of a special ad on block,
there's a special we have to write a special line
of code, namely
the.
The following.
They have to reach following
is more than regular, then we have to put some
brackets.
Right, and then let's go ahead and put that block
in there and then now we have to actually tell us
what what it is. And so we have to do this.
Aalto, wait, no, uh, it's the text to speech at
Unblock. OK, and then we're going to do search.
Voice.
To.
Also.
And now we're going to finish the special blocks
and then we're going to speak. Then now this is
texture. We're going to use an ampersand. Hello,
how are you?
And block, OK? And they were going to broadcast
message one, OK?
Broadcast.
Message one, go ahead and finish that, and then
we're going to put two semicolons here. And what
if what if it's spinning? What if, of course,
you're going to want to write code most project
for multiple
sprites so you can't choose slashes Sprite name.
So this is for Sprite one. And then we're going to
finish this Sprite one code with two back slashes
and we can actually go back to it. So let's say
one does right to.
And then
I clicked.
All right.
And then we're going to know it's not one flight
glitch when
we see.
Receive.
Message.
One, and then we can actually we don't actually
need to do that because it's it's got this here,
which tells, OK,
we're going to read it for everything. It doesn't
we don't need to do this. It would actually mess
up the code if we did this, because we have this
it it tells when when something happens, we need
to do this. And when you do that, this would mess
everything up. And it would the computer wouldn't
be able to read it and it would be like, OK,
everything and anything even outside of it to none
of the code would run. So and then so now we need
to do when I received message one, we're going to
and then we're going to show.
Show
and then wait.
Which is zero point five seconds
and.
Hide, but let's say when I do this multiple times,
so.
Repeat. Three. And we're actually just going to do
that,
but we actually need regular black records for
this.
Regular brak, regular brackets and repeat, let me
repeat three times, so.
Oops.
OK, and then we're going to broadcast, broadcast,
mis broadcast.
Impassioned message to know we're going to end the
code for that spring and then let's say we're
going to go back to spray one again,
I know we can actually go back and forth, so.
This is Sprite once code, but it can also be got
to do this can also but, um.
Whatever I put me here is also Sprite one, so we
can actually go back and forth, back and forth,
and that's what's so cool and we can also just
comment doesn't even have to be in a block. So but
if it is, we need to put it. But if it isn't, we
need to put that there. So let's say hello.
How are you
now, I know, and so we can only put exclamation
marks inside of a comment when it's so actually
when that happens, we need to put two of these
here to tell it, OK?
The comment only stops at this exclamation mark.
That actually depends on what version in the
latest version. I haven't actually published it. I
don't know how to program everything to actually
make the programming language. But, um, you could
actually put it. You can't do it in a block, OK?
You can't do it here. That won't work because it
will shut down all the code below here because you
can't read it there. But anyways.
So.
Let's go ahead and
write this,
and then we're going to do. Luks say.
Ampersand, good bye.
OK, so then to end the entire script, we're going
to do.
SEAL, by the way, to start the script, we're going
to do the same thing. It will only read two of
these. So if you have three of these, then it's
going to be like.
Oh, no, bug, and it's going to shut down all the
code should only put this twice so seal
and then it ends here. So let's go through this
again. One flood and one one flood claimed hide,
and until the computers looks and I'm not going to
switch back drop to thank you. Wait, it's a no. As
you point five seconds, show switch costumes, your
costume, one switch back to your left talking and
then the following is more than regular. And then
that's only for the special box. And then it means
we got to tell it to a special block. Curly
brackets
set voice to allow to speak. Hello, how are you?
I'm not going to broadcast message one. We're
ending that code here. Um.
That's actually
right, and we're ending that Sprite Sprite, too,
when I receive message one, we're going to repeat
this third time we're going to show and then we
have a second and then hide and then show that we
have a second hide and then we're going to
broadcast message 2 That's the end of this.
And then that's the end of that Sprite when Sprite
one. Oh, no.
There's a mistake that I actually did on purpose,
maybe you caught it earlier.
And realize we would know, but you're still if
you're still learning, you might forget to do this.
Let's get to this.
You forgot to do that. OK, so I get that mistake
on purpose, maybe you caught it, maybe you didn't.
That's fine if for those who didn't. It's just an
important reminder. If this ever does get
published, maybe it will. I'm sure a fifth grader
as of making this,
but it's essentially the same as this. It's just a
modified a little to be typed. And I hope you
enjoyed this TSCL tutorial. So let's do one more
thing. Anything outside of it's the last TSCL, but
that's not important.
I'm going to.
And he said, I hope you enjoy this TSCL, I hope
you enjoyed the TSCL.
Bye.